{"Topic": "United Nations Organisation", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "What is the term of United Nations Secretary General?", "op1": "3 years", "op2": "6 years", "op3": "4 years", "op4": "5 years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who was the only Secretary General of the UNO to have died while in office?", "op1": "U Thant", "op2": "Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld", "op3": "Trygve Lie", "op4": "Kurt Waldhiem", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which year was the UNO awarded the Nobel Peace Prize?", "op1": "1975", "op2": "1999", "op3": "2001", "op4": "2006", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "How many member countries did the UNO have on its formation in 1945?", "op1": "45", "op2": "48", "op3": "51", "op4": "54", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which organ of the United Nations has suspended its operations since 1994?", "op1": "Trusteeship Council", "op2": "Economic and Social Council", "op3": "Secretariat", "op4": "International Court of Justice", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many official languages does the United Nations have?", "op1": "5", "op2": "6", "op3": "7", "op4": "4", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the term of the President of the UN General Assembly?", "op1": "4 years", "op2": "2 years", "op3": "1 year", "op4": "5 years", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "UN Secretary General heads which principal organ of the United Nations Organisation?", "op1": "General Assembly", "op2": "Security Council", "op3": "Economic and Social Council", "op4": "The Secretariat"}, {"Question": "Which organ of the UNO functions from Peace Palace in The Hague, The Netherlands?", "op1": "Security Council", "op2": "General Assembly", "op3": "Economic and Social Council", "op4": "International Court of Justice", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "How many non-permanent members are there in the Security Council?", "op1": "10", "op2": "12", "op3": "15", "op4": "8", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What is the term of a non-permanent member of the Security Council?", "op1": "1 year", "op2": "2 years", "op3": "3 years", "op4": "4 years", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What is the term of a judge of the International Court of Justice?", "op1": "5 years", "op2": "7 years", "op3": "8 years", "op4": "9 years", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which organ of the United Nations Organisation is responsible for coordinating the work of its specialised agencies?", "op1": "General Assembly", "op2": "Economic and Social Council", "op3": "Security Council", "op4": "Secretariat", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "When was the United Nations Organisation founded?", "op1": "August 9, 1945", "op2": "October 24, 1944", "op3": "October 24, 1945", "op4": "December 10, 1945", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is NOT a specialized agency of the United Nations Organisation?", "op1": "World Trade Organisation", "op2": "World Health Organisation", "op3": "World Meteorological Organisation", "op4": "World Intellectual Property Organisation", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "How many members does the Economic and Social Council have?", "op1": "15", "op2": "22", "op3": "36", "op4": "54", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "How many countries are the members of the U. N. O. at present? (as of Jan 2016)", "op1": "196", "op2": "189", "op3": "193", "op4": "169", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The United Nations agency concerned with the improvement of standards of education and strengthening international co-operation in this field is :", "op1": "U. N. E. F.", "op2": "U. N. E. S. C. O.", "op3": "U. N. I. C. E. F.", "op4": "U. N. E. D. O.", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not the main organ of the U. N. O. ?", "op1": "General Assembly", "op2": "Security Council", "op3": "Trusteeship Council", "op4": "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many permanent members are there in the Security Council?", "op1": "Three", "op2": "Five", "op3": "Six", "op4": "Four", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "How many Judges are there in the International Court of Justice ?", "op1": "9", "op2": "10", "op3": "11", "op4": "15", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The first Secretary General of the United Nations was :", "op1": "Mrs. Vijai Lakshmi Pandit", "op2": "Trygve Lie", "op3": "Dag hammarskjoeld", "op4": "U. Thant", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who was the first Indian to be the President of U. N. General Assembly ?", "op1": "Natwar Singh", "op2": "V. K. Krishna Menon", "op3": "Smt. Vijay Laxmi Pandit", "op4": "Romesh Bhandari", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following countries is not a permanent member of the UN Security Council ?", "op1": "USA", "op2": "UK", "op3": "France", "op4": "Spain", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The non-permanent members of the Security Council are elected for a period of :", "op1": "two years", "op2": "one year", "op3": "three years", "op4": "four years", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "General Assembly of the United Nations meets in a regular session -", "op1": "once a year", "op2": "twice a year", "op3": "once in two years", "op4": "occasionally", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not one of the official languages of the U.N.O.?", "op1": "French", "op2": "Spanish", "op3": "Arabic", "op4": "Italian", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "On what date did the U. N. O. adopt the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?", "op1": "20th October, 1945", "op2": "24th October, 1945", "op3": "26th June, 1945", "op4": "10th December, 1948", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which specialized agency of UNO lists World Heritage Sites?", "op1": "UNESCO", "op2": "UNICEF", "op3": "UNWTO", "op4": "WWF", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the U.N.O.'s first Secretary General from the African continent?", "op1": "Kofi Anan", "op2": "Boutros Boutros-Ghali", "op3": "Javier Perez de Cuellar", "op4": "Ban Ki-moon", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who coined the term United Nations?", "op1": "Franklin D Roosevelt", "op2": "Harry Truman", "op3": "Winston Churchill", "op4": "Joseph Stalin"}]}